Finding Aid of the Milton Potter Papers, 1890-1924
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Milton Potter Papers, 1890-1924
Potter, Milton, 1873-
UWM Manuscript Collection 73
1.2 cubic ft. (3 boxes)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Miscellaneous papers of a superintendent of schools in Pueblo, Colorado; St. Paul, Minnesota; and Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Consists largely of Potter's professional correspondence concerning support for educational programs and his views on the quality of various school texts. There is almost no information on Potter's administration of the schools. Contains some correspondence with his parents, usually concerning routine family matters, family pictures, and some of Potter's awards. Also includes extensive correspondence (1904-1905) between Potter and his future wife, Camilla (ne Barbara), written during their courtship.
The files are organized alphabetically by personal name or by subject, then chronologically.
Administrative/Restriction Information
There are no access restrictions on the materials, and the collection is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
An unknown donor gave the collection to the Milwaukee Public Library at an unknown date. The Library transferred the collection to the Archives in the spring 1991 (accession 1995-049).
Contents List
- Account Book, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Book Company, 1911-1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Appointment Book, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barbara, Camilla
  - Letters from, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters to, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
- Correspondence
  - 1903-1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1913 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dugan, P.J., 1912-1913 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ginn and Company, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Letters of Recommendation, 1908-1913 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Superintendent of Schools, 1918-1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Personal Correspondence, 1905-1919 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Potter Family, Photographs and Records, 1896-1914, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Pueblo, Colorado, Superintendent of Schools, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- The Society of the Sons of the Revolution, 1890-1913 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- St. Paul, Minnesota, Superintendent of Schools, 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
- Writings, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)